<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3877RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-07T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3877RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-07T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-08T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1500Hi"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1500Lo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>new snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Slab avalanches very trigger-sensitive!</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Above 1500 m avalanche danger in the Allgäu, Ammergau, Werdenfels, and Berchtengaden Alps is considerable; below that altitude it is low. Fresh snowdrift accumulations are the main problem. Danger zones occur esp. in steep ridgeline terrain on SE/S/NW facing slopes and in wind-loaded gullies and bowls. Wherever the snow is bonded like a slab, caution is imperative. The frequency of avalanche prone locations increases with ascending altitude. Slab avalanches can be triggered even by 1 person engaged in winter sports and can reach medium size.&#13;
The often still loose fresh snow can trigger naturally as a loose-snow avalanche in extremely steep terrain, or also be triggered by persons. Apart from the danger of being buried in snow also heed the dangers of being swept along by snow masses or of taking a fall.&#13;
In addition, isolated glide snow avalanches can be expected esp. on very steep slopes with a smooth ground beneath in all aspects natural triggering is possible. Glide cracks are covered, thus, hard to spot. At higher altitudes these releases can reach medium size.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Up to half a meter of new snow was deposited on an ice encrusted old snowpack which is in most places capable of bearing loads. At higher altitudes older snowdrifts are blanketed. Bonding of fresh to old snow/snowdrifts is good at low altitudes, deteriorates with ascending altitude. In places, trigger-sensitive intermediate layers are embedded in the new snow masses. NE winds transport the loose snow very effectively; many new snowdrift accumulations will be generated which are deposited atop loose snow layers. Shooting cracks indicate that the snowpack structure is prone to triggering. The old snowpack is thoroughly moist, often wet down to the ground. Gliding movements over the ground are thereby enhanced.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>As precipitations abate and thanks to stable high pressure weather avalanche danger will continue to recede in the next few days.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-30"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-60"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-11"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3877RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-07T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3877RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-07T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-08T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1500Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1500Lo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>new snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>New snow in places prone to triggering</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Above 1500 m avalanche danger in the foothills of the Bavarian Alps moderate, below that altitude danger is low. Fresh snow is the main problem. In steep rocky terrain it can release naturally as loose snow avalanches. Wherever the snow is bonded like a slab, caution is imperative, i.e., slabs that are usually small can be triggered by a single person engaged in winter sports. Apart from these risks heed the dangers of being swept along by snow masses or of taking a fall.&#13;
In addition, very few isolated glide snow avalanches can be expected esp. on very steep slopes with a smooth ground beneath in all aspects - natural triggering is possible. Glide cracks are covered, thus, hard to spot. Glide snow avalanches tend to be small-sized.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>There has been 20-40 cm of fresh snow registered, deposited on an icy/encrusted old snowpack surface, generally capable of bearing loads. At higher altitudes older snowdrifts are blanketed. Bonding of fresh to old snow/snowdrifts is good at low altitudes, deteriorates with ascending altitude. In some places, graupel is embedded. NE winds transport the loose snow very effectively; many new snowdrift accumulations will be generated which are deposited atop loose snow layers and are prone to triggering. Shooting cracks can indicate that the snowpack structure is prone to triggering. The old snowpack is thoroughly moist, often wet down to the ground. Gliding movements over the ground are thereby enhanced. At low altitudes the fresh snow was deposited directly on bare ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>As precipitations abate and thanks to stable high pressure weather avalanche danger will continue to recede in the next few days.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-41"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-42"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-43"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-51"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-52"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
