<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4403RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-03-07T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4403RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-03-07T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-03-08T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Fresh snowdrift accumulations at high altitudes in places prone to triggering</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is moderate. Main problem: wet snow. Loose snow avalanches can release naturally or be triggered by individuals engaged in wintersports in steep rocky terrain, in particular due to solar radiation. Possibility of natural releases of glide snow avalanches on smooth steep grass-covered slopes. Wet avalanches are small to medium-sized.&#13;
At higher altitudes, snowdrifts are also prone to triggering, in particular in steep ridgeline terrain in W-N-E aspects. These can be triggered as small to medium-sized slabs even by a single skier.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>As a consequence of mild temperatures and solar radiation the snow will become superficially moist on Friday, forfeits its firmness and can be released as loose snow avalanches. At higher altitudes, intensifying winds will transport the snow spatially limited. Fresh and older snowdrifts are found atop soft layers and are prone to triggering. In some places at high altitude the uppermost part of the snowpack contains faceted, expansively metamorphosed crystals underneath a melt-freeze crust which can constitute a weak layer. Elsewhere the old snowpack is compact and stable. It is completely moist and wet down to the ground. A wet layer forms at the ground even underneath the new snow that fell atop a bare ground. Gliding movements over smooth ground become possibl.&#13;
</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger changes little.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-41"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-42"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-43"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-30"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4403RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-03-07T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4403RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-03-07T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-03-08T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Hi"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Lo"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Avalanche danger considerable. Exercise caution and choose a defensive route</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger above 2000 m is considerable, below that altitude danger is moderate. Main problem: wet snow of the last few days which can release naturally in very steep terrain -- in particular due to solar radiation -- as small to medium-sized loose snow avalanches or be triggered by individuals engaged in wintersports. Glide snow avalanches can trigger naturally on smooth steep grass-covered slopes in all aspects, in very few isolated cases they can grow to large size.&#13;
At higher altitudes, the new snow of that fell on Wednesday as well ass fresh snowdrifts are also prone to triggering, in particular in steep ridgeline terrain in W-N-E aspects. They can be triggered as medium-sized slab avalanches by one sole skier.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Solar radiation and mild temperatures will soften the snow superficially on Wednesday, the snow forfeits its firmness and can release as loose snow avalanches. Intensifying winds transports the snow at higher altitudes and deposits it atop soft layers in particular on the shady side, in places atop surface hoar. The snow is prone to triggering. In the new fallen snow of Wednesday, too, there is a weak layer that can be triggered. Many small and medium-sized releases on Thursday confirm that thee weak layers are trigger-sensitive. At high altitudes, the uppermost part of the snowpack in addition contains facted expansively metamorphosed crystals underneath a melt-freeze crust. Elsewhere the old snowpack is compact and stable. It is completely moist and wet down to the ground. A wet layer forms at the ground even underneath the new snow that fell atop a bare ground. Gliding snow masses over smooth ground are the consequence.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Foehn wind can generate fresh snowdrifts on the weekend. The wet-snow problem persists&#13;
</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-12"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4403RGR3">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-03-07T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4403RGR3">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-03-07T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-03-08T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Avoid areas below glide cracks</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is low. Main problem: gliding snow. Isolated smaller glide snow avalanches can trigger naturally on steep grass-covered slopes in all aspects.&#13;
In addition, individual small loose glide snow avalanches are possible in steep rocky terrain.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Following a clear night in many places the snowpack surface is mostly encrusted early in the morning. As the day progresses, the melt-freeze crust softens again due to warming and solar radiation. Up to high altitudes the snowpack is moist and wet down to the ground, thus enabling gliding movements over smooth ground. At high altitudes, spatially limited some snowdrifts can accumulate and some places there is a soft layer underneath a melt-freeze crust - triggerable in isolated cases. Elsewhere the snowpack does not contain any significant weak layers. There is barely any snow below 1500 m.&#13;
</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger changes little.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-51"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-52"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-60"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
