<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4441RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-03-11T15:58:47+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4441RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-03-11T15:58:47+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-03-12T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1400Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1400Lo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>gullies in all aspects, behind discontinuities, above the treeline and at borderlines, in forest clearances</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Fresh snow, freshly generating snowdrifts - assess with caution!</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Above 1400 m avalanche danger is moderate, below that altitude danger is low. Main problem: fresh, trigger-prone snowdrifts. Slab avalanches can be triggered by 1 person in the fresh fallen snow, releases medium-sized. In addition, in extended north-facing terrain, older snowdrift masses from the weekend can still trigger slab avalanches by large additional loading. Beware esp. the entries into steep gullies and bowls, also behind discontinuities, the strong winds can form trigger-prone snowdrift accumulations also in wooded zones. Frequency and size of snowdrifts increase with ascending altitude, hard to recognize  due to poor visibility.&#13;
In extremely steep terrain, repeated dry loose-snow avalanches are possible during the precipitation, releases small-to-medium.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Fresh snow and drifts will be deposited atop a generally stable and thoroughly moist (superficially melt-freeze encrusted) snowpack. Amounts: 25 cm in Totes Gebirge and on Stuhleck, 45 cm in Hochschwab region. Bonding to the old snowpack is good.  On north-facing slopes older snowdrifts are now covered, on south-facing slopes the snow fell on bare ground up to high altitudes or atop wind-compressed snow from the weekend. Inside the fresh and older snow are possibly weak layers, they will initially be prone to triggering. Esp. in zones where snowfall is heavy, snowdrifts can be frequent and large-sized.The snowpack base is often wet, tends to glide over steep smooth slopes.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>A low along the eastern rim of the Alps is bringing snowfall, focal point: from Hochschwab over Mürzsteg Alps to Stuhleck. On Monday evening snowfall from heavy cloud cover, snowfall level at 1100-1300 m. In western Upper Styria, less snowfall, in the southern regions hardly any at all. Nonetheless, skies will be overcast on Tuesday, the higher peaks shrouded in fog. In evening, bright intervals are likely. Strong-to-stormy and cold NW winds. At 2000 m: -4 degrees.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger levels are not expected to change significantly.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-13"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-09"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4441RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-03-11T15:58:47+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4441RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-03-11T15:58:47+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-03-12T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1800Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1800Lo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>gullies in all aspects, behind discontinuities, above the treeline and at borderlines, in forest clearances</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Snowdrifts trigger-prone</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger  above 1800 m is moderate, below that altitude danger is low. Fresh and older drifts at entries from steep gullies and bowls also behind discontinuities, the strong winds can form trigger-prone snowdrift accumulations also in wooded zones.  Frequency and size of snowdrifts increase with ascending altitude, hard to recognize  due to poor visibility.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Fresh and older snowdrift accumulations in transitions from steep gullies and bowls and behind discontinuities can be triggered in places by 1 person. Slabs are mostly small-to-medium. Frequency and size of danger zones increases with ascending altitude, also occur in wooded zones. Some fresh snow and drifts will be deposited atop a generally stable and thoroughly moist (superficially melt-freeze encrusted) snowpack. Amounts: 10 cm from Turrach to Soboth, 25 cm in Niedere Tauern region and Dachstein Massif. Bonding to the old snowpack is good.  On north-faceing slopes older snowdrifts are now covered, on south-facing slopes the snow fell on bare ground up to high altitudes or atop wind-compressed snow from the weekend. Inside the fresh and older snow are possibly weak layers, they will initially be prone to triggering. Esp. in zones where snowfall is heavy, snowdrifts can be frequent and large-sized.&#13;
The snowpack base is often wet, tends to glide over smooth ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>A low along the eastern rim of the Alps is bringing snowfall, focal point: from Hochschwab over Mürzsteg Alps to Stuhleck. On Monday evening snowfall from heavy cloud cover, snowfall level at 1100-1300 m. In western Upper Styria, less snowfall, in the southern regions hardly any at all. Nonetheless, skies will be overcast on Tuesday, the higher peaks shrouded in fog. In evening, bright intervals are likely. Strong-to-stormy and cold NW winds. At 2000 m: -4 degrees.&#13;
</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger levels are not expected to change significantly. Snowdrift problem slowly receding.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-18"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-17"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-15"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-16"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
