<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3842RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-03T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3842RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-03T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-04T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineHi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineLo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>glide-snow avalanches possible at any time of day in all aspects</comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <comment>small, spread-out snowdrift masses</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Circumvent zones below glide cracks. Assess high-altitude snowdrifts with caution.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Naturally trriggered glide-snow avalanches are still the main danger, esp. on steep slopes in all aspects with smooth ground (grass, rocks). Depending on snow depths the fractures can be medium-sized, but at low altitudes the runout zones remain small. Open glide cracks are indicators of potential danger, should be circumvented.&#13;
Since New Year’s Day fresh snowdrift accumulations have continually been generated. Danger zones occur above the timberline esp. in extended east-facing aspects behind discontinuities in terrain transitions, triggerable even by 1 person as a small slab avalanche. In encrusted or icy steep terrain, acute danger of falling. Mostly thin fresh snow and drifts are poorly bonded.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Up to 25 cm of fresh snow fell during the night of New Year’s Eve, most from #Turrach over Zirbitz to Koralpe, much less in Tauern and Northern Alps. Storm westerly winds formed thin drifts, bonding poorly with the encrusted old snowpack surface which is compact and without marked weak layers (a thick melt-freeze crust capable of bearing loads), riddled with water seepage channels, highly unpleasant for skiers. The snowpack is gliding downhill and cracking on its journey.&#13;
The old snowpack is compact, no marked weak layers, riddled with water seepage channels. The snowpack is gliding downhill over smooth ground. Some fresh snowfall and drifts esp. on east-facing slopes, poorly bonded with the encrusted old snowpack surface.&#13;
The snowpack continues to glide downhill over smooth ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>A cold front from the NW will pass through during the morning, slight high-pressure conditions, esp in the Northern Alps heavy cloud with some showers, the snowfall level will lie at 1400 m. In the afternoon clouds will disperse, sunshine will prevail. On the southern flank of the Alps it will be sunny all day long. Stormy westerly winds, only from Turrach to Koralpe will winds be light. At 2000 m: -5 degrees; at 1500 m: -1 degrees. On the southern flank of the Alps, about 3 degrees milder.&#13;
On Friday the high-altitude airstream will shift to southwesterly and it will become foehnig. In the evening, initial precipitation will set in, in the SW regions. On Saturday a low over the Gulf of Genua will bring rain and snow. On Sunday a very cold Arctic air mass will reach us.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger levels are not expected to change significantly.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-09"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-18"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-15"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-17"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-16"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-13"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3842RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-03T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3842RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-03T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-04T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>in very isolated cases</comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <comment>in very isolated cases + small snowdrift masses</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Generally low danger but caution urged towards isolated naturally triggered glide-snow avalanches + snowdrift patches</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Generally low danger, but isolated naturally-triggered glide-snow avalanches cannot be excluded. Danger zones: steep grassy slopes, hillsides, forest clearances. Avoid glide cracks.  New snowdrift accumulations have formed, danger zones occur above the timberline esp. on steep east-facing slopes behind discontinuities, and can be triggered by one person, releasing as a small slab avalanche.  Acute danger of falling.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The old snowpack is compact, no marked weak layers, riddled with water seepage channels. The snowpack is gliding downhill over smooth ground. Some fresh snowfall and drifts esp. on east-facing slopes, poorly bonded with the encrusted old snowpack surface.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>A cold front from the NW will pass through, intermediate high-pressure front conditions will be felt. In the Northern Alps, heavy cloud will dominate until midday, bringing some showers, snowfall level at 1400 m. In the afternoon clouds will disperse, sunshine will prevail. On the southern flank of the Alps it will be sunny all day long. Stormy westerly winds, only from Turrach to Koralpe will winds be light. At 2000 m: -5 degrees; at 1500 m: -1 degrees. On the southern flank of the Alps, about 3 degrees milder.&#13;
On Friday the high-altitude airstream will shift to southwesterly and it will become foehnig. In the evening, initial precipitation will set in, in the SW regions. On Saturday a low over the Gulf of Genua will bring rain and snow. On Sunday a very cold Arctic air mass will reach us.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger levels are not expected to change significantly. Low danger continues.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-14"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
