<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <metaDataProperty>
    <MetaData>
      <dateTimeReport>2025-02-20T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
    </MetaData>
  </metaDataProperty>
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="43cea84b-836a-4674-95e0-fcf1c258dcfc" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-02-20T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-02-20T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-02-21T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-VB-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-VC-01"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Lw"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <dangerPatterns>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP1</type>
            </DangerPattern>
          </dangerPatterns>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>old snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>decreasing</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-02-21T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-02-22T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Individual avalanche prone locations are to be found in steep terrain at high altitudes and in high Alpine regions.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Dry avalanches can be released in the old snowpack and reach medium size in isolated cases. This applies in particular in case of a large load. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Apart from the danger of being buried, restraint should be exercised in particular in view of the danger of avalanches sweeping people along and giving rise to falls. &lt;br/&gt; As a consequence of warming during the day and solar radiation moist avalanches are possible as the day progresses, but they will be mostly small. This applies in particular in steep rocky terrain between approximately 2300 and 2600 m.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The high temperatures on Thursday gave rise to significant moistening of the snowpack over a wide area on sunny slopes. &lt;br/&gt; As a consequence of highly fluctuating temperatures a crust formed on the surface during the last few days, in particular on steep sunny slopes below approximately 2400 m, as well as at low altitude. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Isolated avalanche prone weak layers exist in the old snowpack, especially in areas where the snow cover is rather shallow. &lt;br/&gt; At low altitude less snow than usual is lying. Watch out for the numerous rocks hidden by the little recent snow.</snowpackStructureComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="751d0eeb-0a80-4471-9b38-e69279777cb6" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-02-20T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-02-20T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-02-21T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-VB-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-VB-02"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2300Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2300Lw"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <dangerPatterns>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP1</type>
            </DangerPattern>
          </dangerPatterns>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>old snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2300Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2600Lw"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-02-21T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-02-22T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Individual weak layers exist in the snowpack. The weather conditions will cause a slight weakening of the near-surface layers in the early morning in particular on sunny slopes.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanches can in isolated cases be released in the old snowpack and reach medium size in particular on very steep shady slopes, caution is to be exercised in steep rocky terrain, as well as on steep, little used shady slopes. &lt;br/&gt; Apart from the danger of being buried, restraint should be exercised in particular in view of the danger of avalanches sweeping people along and giving rise to falls. &lt;br/&gt; As a consequence of warming during the day and the solar radiation, the likelihood of dry and moist avalanches being released will increase a little in particular on steep southeast and south facing slopes below approximately 2600 m. Here avalanches are possible in the late morning, but they will be mostly small.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>High altitudes and the high Alpine regions: As a consequence of mild temperatures, low relative humidity and the light wind, the snow drift accumulations stabilised during the last few days. &lt;br/&gt; In shady places that are protected from the wind: Towards its surface, the snowpack is fairly homogeneous; its surface is loosely bonded and consists of surface hoar and faceted crystals. &lt;br/&gt; Very steep sunny slopes: Towards its surface, the snowpack is largely stable and its surface has a melt-freeze crust that is strong in many cases. The high temperatures on Thursday gave rise to significant moistening of the snowpack over a wide area on sunny slopes. &lt;br/&gt; Towards its base, the snowpack is faceted. This applies in particular on steep east, north and northwest facing slopes,.</snowpackStructureComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="e3bfe8dc-251e-4e3d-b80c-bc46a41f06fe" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-02-20T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-02-20T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-02-21T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-03"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2300Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2300Lw"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <dangerPatterns>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP6</type>
            </DangerPattern>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP1</type>
            </DangerPattern>
          </dangerPatterns>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>old snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2300Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-02-21T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-02-22T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Weakly bonded old snow at high altitudes and in high Alpine regions. Slight increase in danger of dry and moist avalanches as a consequence of warming during the day and solar radiation.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanches can in very isolated cases be released in the old snowpack and reach medium size in particular on steep shady slopes. This applies in particular in case of a large load. &lt;br/&gt; Apart from the danger of being buried, restraint should be exercised in particular in view of the danger of avalanches sweeping people along and giving rise to falls. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; As a consequence of warming during the day and solar radiation moist avalanches are possible as the day progresses, but they will be mostly small. This applies in particular on very steep sunny slopes below approximately 2600 m, as well as in steep rocky terrain.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The spring-like weather conditions gave rise to increasing consolidation of the snowpack in particular at low and intermediate altitudes. It is largely stable and its surface has a melt-freeze crust that is strong in many cases, in particular on steep sunny slopes below approximately 2200 m. &lt;br/&gt; The high temperatures on Thursday gave rise to significant moistening of the snowpack on sunny slopes. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; In shady places that are protected from the wind intermediate and high altitudes: Towards its surface, the snowpack is fairly homogeneous; its surface is loosely bonded and consists of surface hoar and faceted crystals. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Towards its base, the snowpack consists of faceted crystals. This applies in particular on steep east, north and northwest facing slopes,.</snowpackStructureComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="e8c56e25-b173-4eda-a391-c7c7c10b5acc" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-02-20T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-02-20T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-02-21T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-01"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <dangerPatterns>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP6</type>
            </DangerPattern>
          </dangerPatterns>
          <avProblems/>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-02-21T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-02-22T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Individual avalanche prone locations are to be found in particular on very steep slopes above approximately 2300 m.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>The avalanche prone locations are to be found in particular in gullies and bowls above approximately 2300 m and on extreme north facing slopes. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Avalanches can as before be released by large loads, but they will be small in most cases. &lt;br/&gt; Watch out for the numerous rocks hidden by the little recent snow.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The snowpack is largely stable. &lt;br/&gt; As a consequence of highly fluctuating temperatures a crust formed on the surface, in particular below approximately 2200 m. The high temperatures on Thursday gave rise to moistening of the snowpack over a wide area on sunny slopes. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; At low altitude less snow than usual is lying.</snowpackStructureComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
