<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4272RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-02-21T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4272RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-02-21T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-02-22T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Hi"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Lo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Frequency of avalanche prone locations increases as the day progresses</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger above 2000 m is considerable, below that altitude danger is low. The main problem are snowdrifts which can be triggered as slab avalanches by minimum additional loading, for example by a single skier. Avalanche prone locations occur on steep ridgeline slopes as well as in wind-loaded gullies and bowls in all aspects. Slab avalanches can reach medium size.&#13;
The snow can trigger naturally in extremely steep rocky and rugged terrain or can be released by a single person engaged in wintersports in steep terrain. Loose snow avalanches are mostly small.&#13;
There is a risk that small to medium-sized glide snow avalanches release spontaneously on very steep slopes over smooth ground that have not yet discharged.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Loose snow is extensively transported all day by heavy southerly wind. At higher altitude it is deposited atop older snowdrift accumulations, a hard old snowpack surface or a melt-freeze crust. Depending on the aspect the latter differs widely, but is hardly capable of bearing crusts. Underneath the melt-freeze crust there are loose and partly trigger-sensitive layers. In leeward and sunny zones the superficial snow moistens fast and forfeits its firmness. Melt-freeze crusts within the old snowpack are dissolving more and more. At high altitudes the snowpack is moist, at intermediate altitudes thoroughly wet, but all in all it is compact and, by and large, stable.On steep slopes the wet snowpack base promotes gliding of the snowpack over steep slopes with smooth ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Temperatures will drop by the weekend and there will be snowfall. Avalanche danger increases.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-12"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4272RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-02-21T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4272RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-02-21T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-02-22T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Lo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Frequency of avalanche prone locations increases as the day progresses</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is moderate above 2000 m, below that altitude danger is low. The main problem are snowdrifts which can be triggered as slab avalanches by minimum additional loading, for example by a single skier. Avalanche prone locations occur on steep ridgeline slopes as well as in wind-loaded gullies and bowls in all aspects. Slab avalanches remain mostly small.&#13;
The snow can trigger naturally in extremely steep rocky and rugged terrain or can be released by a single person engaged in wintersports in steep terrain. Loose snow avalanches are mostly small.&#13;
There is a risk that small glide snow avalanches release spontaneously on very steep slopes over smooth ground that have not yet discharged.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Loose snow is extensively transported all day by heavy southerly wind. At higher altitude it is deposited atop older snowdrift accumulations, a hard old snowpack surface or a melt-freeze crust. Depending on the aspect the latter differs widely, but is hardly capable of bearing loads. Underneath the melt-freeze crust there are loose and partly trigger-sensitive layers. In leeward and sunny zones the superficial snow moistens fast and forfeits its firmness. Melt-freeze crusts within the old snowpack are dissolving more and more. At high altitudes the snowpack is moist, at intermediate altitudes thoroughly wet, but all in all it is compact and, by and large, stable. On steep slopes the wet snowpack base promotes gliding of the snowpack over steep slopes with smooth ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Temperatures will drop by the weekend and there will be snowfall. Avalanche danger increases.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-60"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-30"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4272RGR3">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-02-21T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4272RGR3">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-02-21T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-02-22T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Heed dangers of being swept along by small avalanches and of falling</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is low. Main problem: gliding snow. It is possible that mostly small glide snow avalanches release spontaneously on very steep slopes over smooth ground. &#13;
As a consequence of heat penetration it is in addition to be expected that wet loose snow avalanches trigger naturally in extremely steep rocky and rugged terrain. In steep terrain avalanches can even be triggered by a single person enganged in wintersports. Avalanches tend to be small.&#13;
Likelihood of isolated snowdrifts at ridge and summit levels triggerable as small slab avalanches by a single person engaged in wintersports.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Loose snow is extensively transported all day by heavy southerly wind. In many places the snowdrifts are deposited atop a moist old snowpack surface, at higher ridge and summit altitudes in places also on soft intermediate layers that are prone to triggering. Due to the mild temperatures the snow moistens fast and forfeits its firmness. The old snowpack is predominantly thoroughly wet. All in all it is compact and, by and large, stable. The wet snowpack base promotes gliding of the snowpack over steep slopes with smooth ground. There is barely any snow left below 1500 m.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Temperatures will drop by the weekend and there will be snowfall. Danger of dry avalanches increases.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-41"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-42"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-43"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-51"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-52"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
