<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <metaDataProperty>
    <MetaData>
      <dateTimeReport>2026-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
    </MetaData>
  </metaDataProperty>
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="420afe76-b032-437a-9b82-e49e22eb9ee3" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2026-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2026-02-24T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2026-02-25T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-02"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <dangerPatterns>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP10</type>
            </DangerPattern>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP2</type>
            </DangerPattern>
          </dangerPatterns>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2200Lw"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2026-02-25T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2026-02-26T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Wet and gliding avalanches require caution.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>In particular steep sunny slopes and base of rock walls: Medium-sized and, in isolated cases, large moist and wet avalanches are possible as a consequence of warming. &lt;br/&gt; The older wind slabs can be released in isolated cases at intermediate and high altitudes. These can in some places be released by people and reach medium size. &lt;br/&gt; On steep grassy slopes gliding avalanches and moist snow slides are possible. Areas with glide cracks are to be avoided. &lt;br/&gt; Backcountry tours should be started very early and concluded timely.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>In particular in the vicinity of peaks snow depths vary greatly, depending on the infuence of the wind. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Sunshine and high temperatures will give rise from early morning to rapid moistening of the snowpack in particular on sunny slopes. &lt;br/&gt; Since Friday the weather has been very mild. In particular below the tree line: The surface of the snowpack will freeze very little and will already be soft in the early morning.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>The weather will be very mild. The high humditiy will give rise as the day progresses to increasing moistening of the snowpack in particular at low and intermediate altitudes. Increase in danger of moist and wet avalanches as the moisture increases. Moist avalanches can in some cases release the wet snowpack and reach large size in particular on very steep sunny slopes.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="348b8e25-083a-47d5-ab1a-ae0d3709a10e" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2026-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2026-02-24T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2026-02-25T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-03"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2800Hi"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2800Lw"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <dangerPatterns>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP10</type>
            </DangerPattern>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP6</type>
            </DangerPattern>
          </dangerPatterns>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2800Lw"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2600Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2026-02-25T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2026-02-26T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Rapid increase in danger of moist and wet avalanches as a consequence of warming during the day and solar radiation.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>The weather will be mild. In particular steep sunny slopes and base of rock walls: At low and intermediate altitudes medium-sized and large moist and wet avalanches are possible as the moisture increases. Below approximately 2800 m moist avalanches can penetrate even deep layers. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; The older wind slabs can still be released. Mostly the avalanches are medium-sized and can be released in isolated cases by a single winter sport participant. &lt;br/&gt; Along the border with France the avalanche prone locations are more widespread. &lt;br/&gt; Backcountry tours should be started and concluded early.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>By Saturday sometimes deep wind slabs formed in particular on east, south and southwest facing slopes. In the vicinity of peaks snow depths vary greatly, depending on the infuence of the wind. The strong wind has transported the fresh and old snow. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; In places that are protected from the wind in all altitude zones a lot of snow is lying for the time of year. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Sunshine and high temperatures will give rise from early morning to rapid moistening of the snowpack in particular on sunny slopes. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Since Friday the weather has been very mild. In particular below the tree line: The surface of the snowpack will freeze very little and will already be soft in the early morning.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>The weather will be very mild. The high humditiy will give rise as the day progresses to increasing moistening of the snowpack in particular at low and intermediate altitudes. Increase in danger of moist and wet avalanches as the moisture increases. Ground avalanches are possible in particular in the afternoon.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="0a3e01ee-68dc-4a5d-8b90-7dd4ac3efb7a" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2026-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2026-02-24T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2026-02-25T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-TO-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-CN-03"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <dangerPatterns>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP10</type>
            </DangerPattern>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP6</type>
            </DangerPattern>
          </dangerPatterns>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2026-02-25T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2026-02-26T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Significant increase in danger of moist and wet avalanches as a consequence of warming during the day and solar radiation.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>The weather will be very warm. On very steep sunny slopes and at low and intermediate altitudes medium-sized and, in isolated cases, large moist and wet avalanches are possible as the moisture increases. Below approximately 2600 m moist avalanches can penetrate even deep layers and reach quite a large size. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; The somewhat older wind slabs can be released in some cases. Mostly the avalanches are medium-sized and can mostly be released by large loads, caution is to be exercised in particular at transitions from a shallow to a deep snowpack, as well as at the base of rock walls and behind abrupt changes in the terrain. &lt;br/&gt; Backcountry tours should be started and concluded early.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>In the vicinity of peaks snow depths vary greatly, depending on the infuence of the wind. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; In these regions above approximately 1300 m a lot of snow is lying for the time of year. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; The spring-like weather conditions from the early morning will give rise to rapid moistening of the snowpack in particular on sunny slopes below approximately 2600 m. The surface of the snowpack will soften earlier than the day before. &lt;br/&gt; Isolated medium-sized slab avalanches have been released by people in the last three days.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>The weather will be very warm. The high humditiy will give rise as the day progresses to increasing moistening of the snowpack in particular at low and intermediate altitudes. Increase in danger of moist and wet avalanches as the moisture increases. Ground avalanches are possible in particular in the afternoon.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="6f9b10ed-61e2-4bf0-913d-1ffb6bea6f2f" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2026-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2026-02-24T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2026-02-25T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-VB-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-VC-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-VB-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-21-VB-02"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <dangerPatterns>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP10</type>
            </DangerPattern>
            <DangerPattern>
              <type>DP2</type>
            </DangerPattern>
          </dangerPatterns>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2300Lw"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2026-02-25T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2026-02-26T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>The weather will be warm. The danger of wet and gliding avalanches will already increase in the late morning.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>On sunny slopes and at low and intermediate altitudes medium-sized and, in isolated cases, large moist and wet avalanches are possible as a consequence of warming. In particular below approximately 2600 m moist avalanches can penetrate even deep layers and reach quite a large size. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Gliding avalanches and moist snow slides are possible on steep grassy slopes. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; The weather conditions fostered a gradual stabilisation of the snow drift accumulations. Mostly the avalanches are medium-sized and can be released in some cases by a single winter sport participant, caution is to be exercised in particular at transitions from a shallow to a deep snowpack. &lt;br/&gt; Backcountry tours should be started and concluded early.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>In the vicinity of peaks snow depths vary greatly, depending on the infuence of the wind. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; In some places various wind slab layers are lying on old snow containing large grains. &lt;br/&gt; During the day: The spring-like weather conditions from the early morning will give rise to rapid moistening of the snowpack in particular on sunny slopes below approximately 2600 m. The surface of the snowpack will soften earlier than the day before.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>The weather will be very warm. The high humditiy will give rise as the day progresses to increasing moistening of the snowpack in particular at low and intermediate altitudes. Increase in danger of moist and wet avalanches as the moisture increases. Moist avalanches can in some cases release the wet snowpack and reach large size in particular on very steep sunny slopes.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
