<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4081RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-30T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4081RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-30T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-31T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>favourable situation</type>
              <comment>small/thin drifted masses</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Low avalanche danger, but danger of falling</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is generally low. On high-altitude east-facing slopes there are isolated snowdrift patches. Isolated wet slides possible in Gurktal and Seetal Alps.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Due to rising temperatures then subsequent cooling, the snowpack has regained firmness. At high altitudes it is hard and icy, at intermediate altitudes moist-to-wet.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>The airstream is shifting to northwesterly, cooler air masses are moving in, including cloudbanks and intermittent sunshine. Nevertheless, one more day will remain dry, with light winds. At 2000 m: +1 degrees.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>South of the Mur/Mürz rift, sunshine to start with, slowly becoming overcast. At midday from the north, light snowfall will set in, intensifying somewhat in the afternoon. Snowfall level will drop from 1500 m down to 1000 m by evening. In the rimline ranges, only isolated snow and sleet showers. Due to the precipitation the NW winds in northern regions will intensify. At 2000 m at midday: -2 degrees, subsequently getting much colder. &#13;
Avalanche danger levels are not expected to change significantly.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-14"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-13"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-15"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-16"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-17"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-18"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4081RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-30T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4081RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-30T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-31T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>favourable situation</type>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Isolated danger zones at high altitudes</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is low. Above 2200 m, older snowdrift accumulations can be triggered by large additional loading. The few danger zones in backcountry touring areas lie at summit level behind discontinuities and on leeward slopes. Isolated wet loose-snow avalanches are possible. Acute danger of falling on hard and icy surfaces.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Due to mild temperatures the snowpack has become moist up to high altitudes. With subsequent cooling, the snowpack has regained firmness. The surface at high altitudes is hard and icy, at intermediate altitudes moist-to-wet. On steep shady slopes, expansive metamorphosis is weakening the snowpack base.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>The airstream is shifting to northwesterly, cooler air masses are moving in, including cloudbanks and intermittent sunshine. Nevertheless, one more day will remain dry, with light winds. At 2000 m: +1 degrees.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>On Thursday the peaks in the Northern Alps will be veiled in heavy cloud, visibility reduced. At midday from the north, light snowfall will set in, intensifying somewhat in the afternoon. Snowfall level will drop from 1500 m down to 1000 m by evening. In the rimline ranges, only isolated snow and sleet showers. Due to the precipitation the NW winds in northern regions will intensify. At 2000 m at midday: -2 degrees, subsequently getting much colder. &#13;
Avalanche danger levels are expected to slightly increase.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-09"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-02"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
