<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4267RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-02-20T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4267RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-02-20T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-02-21T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1800Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1800Lo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>&gt;2000 steep ridgeline terrain, behind discontinuities, in wind-loaded gullies and bowls</comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>&lt;2600 m glide-snow avalanches on steep smooth slopes</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Pay close heed to snowdrift accumulations with ascending altitude</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Freshly generated snowdrift accumulations are prone to triggering. Danger zones occur in steep ridgeline terrain, behind discontinutiies and in wind-loaded gullies and bowls and increase with ascending altitude. A small-to-medium slab avalanche can be triggered by 1 person. Activities in backcountry demand experience in outlying terrain and the ability to assess avalanche dangers on-site.. Naturally triggered loose-snow avalanches in rocky steep terrain are possible. Glide-snow avalanches can trigger below 2600 m at any time of day or night and reach medium size. Caution urged below glide cracks.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Fresh snow and drifts were able to settle somewhat. On high-altitude shady slopes they lie deposited atop soft layers, otherwise atop a hard old snowpack surface. Bonding is generally good. Weak trigger-prone layers are evident inside the fresh snowdrift accumulations. In addition,  in high shady terrain there are near-surface weak layers evident which are trigger-prone. Warm ground and the wet snowpack base reinforce the gliding movements of the entire snowpack. Frequent glide-snow avalanches have been reported. At lower altitudes the latest fresh snow lies on bare ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>Nocturnal hours: high-altitude clouds, but no precipitation. Wednesday daytime: pleasant weather, good visibility, some cloudbanks but the sun will dominate. In the course of the afternoon the clouds will become heavier. At 2000 m: +2 degrees. Moderate to brisk W/SW winds.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Thursday will have foehn-induced conditions, very mild, strong westerly winds (in foehn lanes, southerly winds). Avalanche danger levels are not expected to change significantly, but fresh snowdrifts can accumulate. Glide-snow/wet-snow avalanche danger will persist.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-03-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-03-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-05-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-05-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-06"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
