<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3809RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2023-12-30T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3809RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2023-12-30T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2023-12-31T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>steep slopes with smooth ground (grass, rocks)</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Mostly low danger. Caution: encrusted icy steep terrain and below glide cracks.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>With increasing altitude, and mostly in extremely steep shady terrain small avalanches can be triggered in near-surface layers. The risks of falling need consideration, esp. on hard, icy steep slopes. A cautious route selection is advised. Danger of glide-snow avalanches, although their activity has receded: on steep smooth slopes in all aspects below 2200 m, small-to-medium releases are possible, difficult to assess, possible at any time of day. Circumvent glide cracks.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The snowpack is well consolidated and stable by and large. The melt-freeze crust is capable of bearing loads up to high altitudes. Many surfaces are wind-impacted or icy from the rainfall. Crests and ridges are utterly windblown, gullies and bowls and zones behind protruberances are filled with older hardened snowdrifts. At intermediate altitudes the snowpack is often moist down to the ground. The weight-load of the fresh snow reinforces the process of gliding over smooth ground, although its activity has receded. In the Prealps, very little snow on the ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>Nocturnal hours: Dry. Mostly clear skies with a few cirrus clouds. Sunday daytime: Disperse clouds to start with, getting cloudier as the day progresses, with diffuse light conditions, the peaks becoming veiled in fog. At 2000 m: 0 degrees, dropping to -5 degrees. Brisk S/W winds.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>New Year’s Eve will bring some fresh snowfall. On Monday the clouds will disperse somewhat. Temperatures will drop. The danger of dry-snow avalanches could increase slightly due to snowdrifts. Danger of small glide-snow avalanches persists.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-02"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3809RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2023-12-30T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3809RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2023-12-30T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2023-12-31T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Hi"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Lo"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>&lt;2400 m steep slopes with smooth ground (grass, rocks)</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Glide-snow avalanches persist, mostly favourable conditions</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is  moderate due to gliding snow. On steep smooth slopes in all aspects above 2400 m, medium glide-snow avalanches are possible, indicated by glide cracks (should be circumvented).&#13;
Danger of dry-snow avalanches is low. With increasing altitude, and mostly in extremely steep shady terrain small avalanches can be triggered in near-surface layers. The risks of falling need consideration, esp. on hard, icy steep slopes. A cautious route selection is advised.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The snowpack is well consolidated and stable by and large. The melt-freeze crust is capable of bearing loads up to high altitudes. Many surfaces are wind-impacted or icy from the rainfall. Crests and ridges are utterly windblown, gullies and bowls and zones behind protruberances are filled with older hardened snowdrifts. At intermediate altitudes the snowpack is often moist down to the ground. The weight-load of the fresh snow reinforces the process of gliding over smooth ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>Nocturnal hours: Dry. Mostly clear skies with a few cirrus clouds. Sunday daytime: Disperse clouds to start with, getting cloudier as the day progresses, with diffuse light conditions, the peaks becoming veiled in fog. At 2000 m: 0 degrees, dropping to -5 degrees. Brisk S/W winds.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>New Year’s Eve will bring some fresh snowfall. On Monday the clouds will disperse somewhat. Temperatures will drop. The danger of dry-snow avalanches could increase slightly due to snowdrifts. Danger of small glide-snow avalanches persists.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-03-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-03-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-05-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-05-02"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
