<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3781RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2023-12-27T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3781RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2023-12-27T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2023-12-28T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Pay heed to danger of taking a fall on icy surfaces!</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is low. Main problem: glide snow. Possibility of isolated glide snow avalanches on steep slopes with smooth ground and still enough snow. They can release spontaneously in any aspect and at any time of day or night and tend to remain small. Glide cracks indicate danger zones.&#13;
In isolated cases small slabs can still be triggered adjacent to ridges and on the shady side in very steep high altitude terrain, as a rule only by large additional loading such as a person walking on foot or a group of skiers.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>With clear skies during Wednesday night, a melt-freeze crust can form that is capable of bearing loads. The crust softens slowly during the course of day; in the shade it will mostly stay icy. Underneath the melt-freeze crust the snowpack is thoroughly moist and frequently wet down to the ground. Therefore, gliding movements over smooth ground are possible. On very steep shady slopes weak layers can still be found in isolated cases. Below 1400 m the ground is becoming bare. In the Bavarian Alps it is now almost impossible  to go backcountry skiing without having to carry the skis for part of the route.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger is not expected to change significantly until Friday.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-41"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-42"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-43"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-51"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-52"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3781RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2023-12-27T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3781RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2023-12-27T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2023-12-28T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Hi"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Lo"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>old snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Pay heed to collapsing cornices and danger of taking a fall on icy surfaces!</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is moderate below 2400 m, above that altitude it is low. Main problem: glide snow. Below approx. 2400 m possibility of glide snow avalanches on steep slopes with smooth ground and still enough snow. They can release in any aspect and at any time of day or night. At higher altitudes glide snow avalanches can grow to medium size; elsewhere they are mostly small. Glide cracks indicate danger zones. With increasing altitude there are isolated trigger-sensitive locations in the old snow where snow is rather shallow as well as at entries into gullies and bowls. Slab avalanches are mostly only triggerable by large additional loading, such as by a person walking on foot.  Slab avalanches can reach medium size.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>With clear skies during Wednesday night, a very hard melt-freeze crust can form that is capable of bearing loads. The crust can soften in in some places during the course of day; in the shade it will mostly stay icy. Underneath the melt-freeze crust the snowpack is thoroughly moist up to high altitudes and frequently wet down to the ground. Therefore, gliding movements over smooth ground are possible at any time. On very steep shady slopes weak layers can still be found in isolated cases near melt-freeze crusts. The snowpack depths vary considerably; ridges and crests are utterly wind blown. Below 1400 m the ground is becoming bare. In the Bavarian Alps it is almost impossible  to go backcountry skiing without having to carry the skis for part of the route.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger is not expected to change significantly until Friday.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-30"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-60"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
