<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4610RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-03-31T16:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4610RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-03-31T16:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-04-01T16:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <comment>possible at any time of day or night</comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>hefty impulse of warmth</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Storm-strength southerly foehn wind</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Wet-snow problem: in all aspects, rocky terrain often the starting zone. Danger zones increase with solar radiation. Larger avalanches are possible in isolated cases, also in low altitude, flat-terrain zones.&#13;
Gliding snow problem: in all aspects, esp. on steep grass-covered slopes. Start: zones with glide-cracks, shooting cracks. Avoid zones near them! They are possible at any time of day or night. Larger avalanches are possible in isolated cases, also in low altitude, flat-terrain zones.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>High temperatures over the last few days have done harsh work on the snowpack, it has forfeited its firmness. The snow base is wet, the surface generally soft already in early morning. In spite of storm-strength winds, hardly any new snowdrifts have been generated. But gliding snow masses have increased. The slopes are becoming bare of snow.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>On Easter Monday, initially storm-strength southerly winds blowing over the mountains, reaching 80-100 km/hr, gusts at high altitudes reaching 120 km/hr. From Fishbach Alps to Koralpe, quite sunny weather, but in western regions clouds from a cold front will move in, rainfall will follow. The front will move eastwards as the day progresses, bringing rainfall/snowfall by evening, snowfall level dropping temporarily to 1200 m. Winds will shift to northwesterly, slacken off gradually. At 2000 m: from 6 degrees dropping to -2 degrees by late evening.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>On Tuesday, clouds and sunshine will alternate. In afternoon, convective cloud build-up esp. in southern regions will increase the tendency towards showers, snow showers above 1600 m. At 2000 m: 0 degrees. Brisk NW winds will be blowing. The wet-snow and gliding snow problems will recede at high altitudes.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-09"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-18"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-17"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
