<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3886RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-08T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3886RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-08T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-09T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <comment>behind discontinuities, small/thin drifted masses</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Generally low danger but snowdrift patches at summit level</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is low in general. Near ridges and behind discontinuities in the terrain, thin snowdrift patches have formed which can be triggered even by 1 person, but only small releases are generated.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The fresh snow from the weekend was transported to E/S facing slopes and on Tuesday, when winds shift, will be transported eastwards to west-facing slopes. The snowdrift accumulations are small. On E/S facing slopes they cover patches of loose fresh snow. On west-facing slopes the fresh drifts lie deposited atop surface hoar. Both of these are potential weak layers. The old snowpack beneath them is compact, without marked weak layers.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>Following a night of clear skies, heavy cloud cover will move in from the southeast on Tuesday morning. The summits will be shrouded in clouds, visibility will be reduced and a bit of light snowfall is possible. At 2000 m: between -8 and -10 degrees. Strong easterly winds will arise during the course of the day.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Wednesday will bring cold but sunny weather, accompanied by strong southerly winds. Avalanche danger will remain low.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-14"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3886RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-08T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3886RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-08T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-09T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineHi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineLo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <comment>atop unfavorable base, behind discontinuities</comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>in isolated cases</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Cold easterly winds depositing snowdrift patches on west-facing slopes</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger above the treeline is moderate. Main problem: snowdrift which have accumulated on E/S/W facing slopes. Danger zones occur in ridgeline terrain, at entries into gullies and bowls and behind discontinuities. Wherever the snow is bonded like a slab, medium-sized avalanches can be triggered even by 1 person. Frequency of danger zones increases with ascending altitude.&#13;
In all aspects, isolated naturally triggered glide-snow avalanches can be expected. Avoid zones below glide cracks.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Following a night of clear skies, heavy cloud cover will move in from the southeast on Tuesday morning. The summits will be shrouded in clouds, visibility will be reduced and a bit of light snowfall is possible. On west-facing slopes the fresh drifts will be deposited atop surface hoar, which is a weak layer. The old snowpack is compact, without marked weak layers, only on shady high-altitude slopes where snow is shallow are there faceted layers lurking. At 2000 m: between -8 and -10 degrees. Strong easterly winds will arise during the course of the day.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>Following a night of clear skies, heavy cloud cover will move in from the southeast on Tuesday morning. The summits will be shrouded in clouds, visibility will be reduced and a bit of light snowfall is possible. At 2000 m: between -8 and -10 degrees. Strong easterly winds will arise during the course of the day in the Northern Alps and the rimline ranges.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Wednesday will bring cold but sunny weather, accompanied by strong southerly winds. Avalanche danger will remain under the threat of snowdrifts, new danger zones will form on north-facing slopes.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-09"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-18"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-17"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-13"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-15"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-16"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-01"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
