<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4156RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-02-08T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4156RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-02-08T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-02-09T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Danger of glide snow avalanches persists.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is low. Glide snow avalanche danger persists which can release naturally at any time on individual very steep slopes with smooth ground in any aspect. In isolated cases these can grow to medium size. Avoid zones below glide cracks. In addition, possibility of isolated wet loose snow slides in extremely steep terrain.&#13;
Small snowdrifts have been generated at high altitudes. Avalanche prone locations are found on steep NW-N-E facing slopes adjacent to ridgelines, as well as in gullies and bowls filled with wind transported snow. Slab avalanches can be released by a single skier. Releases are mostly small. Heed danger of being swept along. Danger of taking a fall on hard snowpack surface.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The snowpack is predominantly stable and compact. Intermediate layers are dissolving more and more. In many places the snowpack is completely moist and wet down to the ground.The consequence are gliding movements on steep slopes with smooth ground. At intermediate altitude the snowpack is in many places soft and forfeits its firmness. In zones with little snow it is now barely capable of bearing loads. In wind-exposed higher altitude terrain, especially in foehn clearances, the snowpack surface is mostly hard. The small loose snow quantities at high altitude are transported and are in some places deposited atop a near-surface weak layer consisting of faceted crystals. At intermediate altitude the snowpack becomes more and more shallow; below approximately 1300 m there is barely any snow left.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Saturday night will be chillier with onset of precipitation. Avalanche danger will increase somewhat. </tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-42"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-43"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-51"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-52"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-41"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-60"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-30"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-11"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
