<bulletins xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V6.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS">
  <bulletin bulletinID="de50a1cb-639c-4de9-b5db-2cadf559c098" lang="en">
    <publicationTime>2025-12-19T16:00:00Z</publicationTime>
    <validTime>
      <startTime>2025-12-19T23:00:00Z</startTime>
      <endTime>2025-12-20T23:00:00Z</endTime>
    </validTime>
    <unscheduled>false</unscheduled>
    <region regionID="IT-21-CN-01">
      <name>Alpi Cozie Sud di confine</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-CN-02">
      <name>Alpi Marittime Occidentali</name>
    </region>
    <dangerRating>
      <mainValue>moderate</mainValue>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
    </dangerRating>
    <avalancheProblem>
      <problemType>new_snow</problemType>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <lowerBound>1800</lowerBound>
      </elevation>
      <aspect>W</aspect>
      <aspect>NE</aspect>
      <aspect>NW</aspect>
      <aspect>N</aspect>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
      <snowpackStability>poor</snowpackStability>
      <frequency>some</frequency>
      <avalancheSize>2</avalancheSize>
    </avalancheProblem>
    <avalancheProblem>
      <problemType>wet_snow</problemType>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <upperBound>2400</upperBound>
      </elevation>
      <aspect>S</aspect>
      <aspect>SW</aspect>
      <aspect>E</aspect>
      <aspect>W</aspect>
      <aspect>SE</aspect>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
      <snowpackStability>poor</snowpackStability>
      <frequency>some</frequency>
      <avalancheSize>2</avalancheSize>
    </avalancheProblem>
    <weatherForecast/>
    <avalancheActivity>
      <highlights>The new snow of the last few days is in isolated cases prone to triggering above approximately 1800 m.</highlights>
      <comment>The new snow can still be released in some cases in particular on west to north to northeast facing aspects above approximately 1800 m. This applies even in case of a single winter sport participant in some cases. Avalanches can in particular reach medium size in isolated cases. &lt;br/> &lt;br/> The high humditiy will give rise as the day progresses to moistening of the snowpack in particular at low and intermediate altitudes. On steep east, southeast and south facing slopes and on steep sunny slopes more small and medium-sized moist avalanches are possible as the penetration by moisture increases. &lt;br/> Snow sport activities outside marked and open pistes call for defensive route selection. The avalanche prone locations are to be found in particular on steep slopes and in gullies and bowls, and behind abrupt changes in the terrain.</comment>
    </avalancheActivity>
    <snowpackStructure>
      <comment>Over a wide area 40 to 50 cm of snow, and even more in some localities, fell in the last few days above approximately 1500 m. &lt;br/> &lt;br/> The high humditiy gave rise to increasing settling of the snowpack at low and intermediate altitudes. The covering of new snow is moist and its surface has a melt-freeze crust. This applies in particular below approximately 1900 m, as well as on sunny slopes. &lt;br/> &lt;br/> Shady slopes, high Alpine regions: The snowpack is fairly homogeneous; its surface consists of loosely bonded snow.</comment>
    </snowpackStructure>
    <travelAdvisory/>
    <tendency>
      <highlights>As a consequence of falling temperatures, the natural activity of moist avalanches will decrease.</highlights>
      <tendencyType>decreasing</tendencyType>
      <validTime>
        <startTime>2025-12-20T23:00:00Z</startTime>
        <endTime>2025-12-21T23:00:00Z</endTime>
      </validTime>
    </tendency>
    <customData>
      <ALBINA>
        <mainDate>2025-12-20</mainDate>
      </ALBINA>
      <LWD_Tyrol>
        <dangerPatterns>DP6</dangerPatterns>
      </LWD_Tyrol>
    </customData>
  </bulletin>
  <bulletin bulletinID="575e131c-ec60-4798-870b-a3efe07ebd76" lang="en">
    <publicationTime>2025-12-19T16:00:00Z</publicationTime>
    <validTime>
      <startTime>2025-12-19T23:00:00Z</startTime>
      <endTime>2025-12-20T23:00:00Z</endTime>
    </validTime>
    <unscheduled>false</unscheduled>
    <region regionID="IT-21-TO-01">
      <name>Alpi Graie di confine</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-CN-04">
      <name>Alpi Marittime Orientali</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-TO-04">
      <name>Alpi Cozie</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-CN-05">
      <name>Alpi Liguri</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-TO-05">
      <name>IT-21-TO-05</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-TO-02">
      <name>Alpi Cozie Nord di confine</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-CN-03">
      <name>Alpi Cozie Sud</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-TO-03">
      <name>Alpi Graie</name>
    </region>
    <dangerRating>
      <mainValue>low</mainValue>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <upperBound>2300</upperBound>
      </elevation>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
    </dangerRating>
    <dangerRating>
      <mainValue>moderate</mainValue>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <lowerBound>2300</lowerBound>
      </elevation>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
    </dangerRating>
    <avalancheProblem>
      <problemType>persistent_weak_layers</problemType>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <lowerBound>2300</lowerBound>
      </elevation>
      <aspect>E</aspect>
      <aspect>NE</aspect>
      <aspect>NW</aspect>
      <aspect>N</aspect>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
      <snowpackStability>poor</snowpackStability>
      <frequency>some</frequency>
      <avalancheSize>2</avalancheSize>
    </avalancheProblem>
    <weatherForecast/>
    <avalancheActivity>
      <highlights>Individual avalanche prone locations are to be found on very steep shady slopes at high altitudes and in high Alpine regions.</highlights>
      <comment>Individual avalanche prone locations are to be found in steep terrain at high altitudes and in high Alpine regions and adjacent to ridgelines and in gullies and bowls. This applies in particular along the border with France. Isolated avalanche prone weak layers exist in the bottom section of the snowpack on steep northwest, north and northeast facing slopes. Weak layers in the lower part of the snowpack can be released in isolated cases by individual winter sport participants here. Avalanches can be released in near-ground layers and reach medium size. &lt;br/> &lt;br/> Be careful of the numerous rocks hidden by the little snow.</comment>
    </avalancheActivity>
    <snowpackStructure>
      <comment>In all aspects as well as in all altitude zones only a small amount of snow is lying for the time of year. &lt;br/> &lt;br/> 10 to 20 cm of snow fell in the last few days above approximately 1700 m. Especially shady slopes high altitudes and the high Alpine regions: The covering of new snow is dry; its surface consists of loosely bonded snow. Faceted weak layers exist in the bottom section of the snowpack on steep north, northeast and northwest facing slopes. &lt;br/> &lt;br/> The high humditiy gave rise to moistening of the snowpack over a wide area at low and intermediate altitudes. &lt;br/> On southeast, south and southwest facing slopes as well as at low altitude from a snow sport perspective, in most cases insufficient snow is lying.</comment>
    </snowpackStructure>
    <travelAdvisory/>
    <tendency>
      <highlights>The weather conditions as the day progresses will give rise to increasing consolidation of the snowpack.</highlights>
      <tendencyType>decreasing</tendencyType>
      <validTime>
        <startTime>2025-12-20T23:00:00Z</startTime>
        <endTime>2025-12-21T23:00:00Z</endTime>
      </validTime>
    </tendency>
    <customData>
      <ALBINA>
        <mainDate>2025-12-20</mainDate>
      </ALBINA>
      <LWD_Tyrol>
        <dangerPatterns>DP1</dangerPatterns>
      </LWD_Tyrol>
    </customData>
  </bulletin>
  <bulletin bulletinID="71b633c4-7a13-4d24-8755-fc8aca7cf045" lang="en">
    <publicationTime>2025-12-19T16:00:00Z</publicationTime>
    <validTime>
      <startTime>2025-12-19T23:00:00Z</startTime>
      <endTime>2025-12-20T23:00:00Z</endTime>
    </validTime>
    <unscheduled>false</unscheduled>
    <region regionID="IT-21-VB-03">
      <name>Alpi Lepontine Sud</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-VC-01">
      <name>Alpi Pennine</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-VB-01">
      <name>Alpi Pennine di confine</name>
    </region>
    <region regionID="IT-21-VB-02">
      <name>Alpi Lepontine Nord</name>
    </region>
    <dangerRating>
      <mainValue>low</mainValue>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <upperBound>2200</upperBound>
      </elevation>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
    </dangerRating>
    <dangerRating>
      <mainValue>moderate</mainValue>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <lowerBound>2200</lowerBound>
      </elevation>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
    </dangerRating>
    <avalancheProblem>
      <problemType>wind_slab</problemType>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <lowerBound>2200</lowerBound>
      </elevation>
      <aspect>E</aspect>
      <aspect>NE</aspect>
      <aspect>N</aspect>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
      <snowpackStability>poor</snowpackStability>
      <frequency>some</frequency>
      <avalancheSize>2</avalancheSize>
    </avalancheProblem>
    <avalancheProblem>
      <problemType>persistent_weak_layers</problemType>
      <elevation uom="m">
        <lowerBound>2200</lowerBound>
      </elevation>
      <aspect>E</aspect>
      <aspect>NE</aspect>
      <aspect>NW</aspect>
      <aspect>N</aspect>
      <validTimePeriod>all_day</validTimePeriod>
      <snowpackStability>poor</snowpackStability>
      <frequency>some</frequency>
      <avalancheSize>2</avalancheSize>
    </avalancheProblem>
    <weatherForecast/>
    <avalancheActivity>
      <highlights>Wind slabs at elevated altitudes. Restraint should be exercised because avalanches can sweep people along and give rise to falls.</highlights>
      <comment>The new snow and wind slabs of the last two days are lying on the unfavourable surface of an old snowpack on northwest to north to east facing aspects above approximately 2200 m. &lt;br/> The avalanche prone locations are to be found in particular on steep shady slopes at high altitudes and in high Alpine regions and adjacent to ridgelines and in gullies and bowls. &lt;br/> Whumpfing sounds and the formation of shooting cracks when stepping on the snowpack are a clear indication. &lt;br/> Mostly the avalanches are small but can be released in isolated cases even by a single winter sport participant. &lt;br/> &lt;br/> The numerous rocks hidden by the recent snow are the main danger.</comment>
    </avalancheActivity>
    <snowpackStructure>
      <comment>15 to 30 cm of snow has fallen since Tuesday above approximately 1500 m. &lt;br/> The new snow and wind slabs of Tuesday are lying on the unfavourable surface of an old snowpack in particular on shady slopes at intermediate and high altitudes. &lt;br/> At high altitudes and in high Alpine regions snow depths vary greatly, depending on the infuence of the wind. &lt;br/> &lt;br/> Below approximately 2000 m from a snow sport perspective, insufficient snow is lying. &lt;br/></comment>
    </snowpackStructure>
    <travelAdvisory/>
    <tendency>
      <highlights>The weather conditions as the day progresses will give rise to increasing consolidation of the snowpack. The avalanche danger will persist.</highlights>
      <tendencyType>steady</tendencyType>
      <validTime>
        <startTime>2025-12-20T23:00:00Z</startTime>
        <endTime>2025-12-21T23:00:00Z</endTime>
      </validTime>
    </tendency>
    <customData>
      <ALBINA>
        <mainDate>2025-12-20</mainDate>
      </ALBINA>
      <LWD_Tyrol>
        <dangerPatterns>DP6</dangerPatterns>
        <dangerPatterns>DP1</dangerPatterns>
      </LWD_Tyrol>
    </customData>
  </bulletin>
</bulletins>
