<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <metaDataProperty>
    <MetaData>
      <dateTimeReport>2025-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
    </MetaData>
  </metaDataProperty>
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="179d13d0-eb4f-495e-b944-43fb35e32faf" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-02-24T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-02-25T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-22"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-14"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2200Hi"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2200Lw"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2200Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validElevation>
                <elevationRange uom="m">
                  <beginPosition>1900</beginPosition>
                  <endPosition>2400</endPosition>
                </elevationRange>
              </validElevation>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>increasing</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-02-25T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-02-26T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>As a consequence of snowfall above approximately 1300 m and the moderate to strong southwesterly wind, fresh snow drift accumulations will form in the course of the day.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>The fresh snow and the wind slabs can be released by a single winter sport participant above approximately 2200 m. They can be released and reach medium size. Such avalanche prone locations are to be found on very steep slopes and in gullies and bowls, and behind abrupt changes in the terrain. &lt;br/&gt; The prevalence of the avalanche prone locations will increase in the afternoon. The prevalence of these will increase at high altitude and in the high Alpine regions. The fresh wind slabs are barely recognisable because of the poor visibility. &lt;br/&gt; As the temperature drops hardly any more moist avalanches are possible. &lt;br/&gt; Gliding avalanches can also occur at any time. Areas with glide cracks are to be avoided as far as possible.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Over a wide area 20 to 30 cm of snow, and even more in some localities, will fall on Tuesday above approximately 2000 m. In some localities 5 cm of snow fell yesterday above approximately 2000 m. &lt;br/&gt; Steep sunny slopes: As a consequence of highly fluctuating temperatures a crust formed on the surface during the last few days. &lt;br/&gt; Especially below approximately 2500 m sunny slopes: Relatively hard layers of snow are lying on a moist old snowpack. &lt;br/&gt; In shady places that are protected from the wind: Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. &lt;br/&gt; Especially steep north, northeast and northwest facing slopes: Towards its base, the snowpack consists of faceted crystals. &lt;br/&gt; Snow depths vary greatly above approximately 2200 m, depending on the infuence of the wind. Adjacent to ridgelines and in pass areas and at high altitude a little snow is lying. At low altitude less snow than usual is lying. &lt;br/&gt; In the south-east of the region, watch out for the numerous rocks hidden by the little recent snow.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>On Wednesday as a consequence of new snow and wind there will be an increase in the danger of dry avalanches within the current danger level.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="70d8b430-24fa-49d4-ba80-32c1d6e85b44" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-02-24T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-02-25T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-16"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-17"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-15"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-18"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Lw"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2000Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validElevation>
                <elevationRange uom="m">
                  <beginPosition>1900</beginPosition>
                  <endPosition>2400</endPosition>
                </elevationRange>
              </validElevation>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>increasing</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-02-25T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-02-26T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>As a consequence of snowfall above approximately 1300 m and the moderate to strong southwesterly wind, fresh snow drift accumulations will form in the course of the day.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>The fresh snow and in particular the wind slabs can be released by a single winter sport participant above approximately 2000 m. The fresh wind slabs can be released and reach medium size. Such avalanche prone locations are to be found on extremely steep slopes and in gullies and bowls, and behind abrupt changes in the terrain. &lt;br/&gt; The prevalence of the avalanche prone locations will increase in the afternoon. The fresh wind slabs are barely recognisable because of the poor visibility. &lt;br/&gt; As the temperature drops hardly any more moist avalanches are possible. &lt;br/&gt; Gliding avalanches can also occur at any time. Areas with glide cracks are to be avoided as far as possible.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Over a wide area 20 to 30 cm of snow will fall on Tuesday above approximately 2000 m. In some localities 5 cm of snow fell yesterday above approximately 2000 m. &lt;br/&gt; Steep sunny slopes: As a consequence of highly fluctuating temperatures a crust formed on the surface during the last few days. &lt;br/&gt; Especially below approximately 2500 m sunny slopes: Relatively hard layers of snow are lying on a moist old snowpack. &lt;br/&gt; In shady places that are protected from the wind: Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. &lt;br/&gt; Especially steep north, northeast and northwest facing slopes: Towards its base, the snowpack consists of faceted crystals. &lt;br/&gt; Snow depths vary greatly above approximately 2200 m, depending on the infuence of the wind. Adjacent to ridgelines and in pass areas and at high altitude a little snow is lying. At low altitude less snow than usual is lying. &lt;br/&gt; In the south-east of the region, watch out for the numerous rocks hidden by the little recent snow.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>On Wednesday as a consequence of new snow and wind there will be an increase in the danger of dry avalanches within the current danger level.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="45bfe30d-f875-4799-a40b-53bacede0f34" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-02-24T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-02-24T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-02-25T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-23"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-24"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-13"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-21"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-25"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-26"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-09"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-19"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-08"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2200Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2200Lw"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2200Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validElevation>
                <elevationRange uom="m">
                  <beginPosition>1900</beginPosition>
                  <endPosition>2400</endPosition>
                </elevationRange>
              </validElevation>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-02-25T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-02-26T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>As a consequence of snowfall above approximately 1300 m and the moderate to strong southwesterly wind, fresh snow drift accumulations will form in the course of the day.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>The small quantity of fresh snow and in particular the mostly small wind slabs can be released by a single winter sport participant in some cases above approximately 2200 m. Apart from the danger of being buried, restraint should be exercised in particular in view of the danger of avalanches sweeping people along and giving rise to falls. Such avalanche prone locations are to be found on very steep slopes and in gullies and bowls, and behind abrupt changes in the terrain. The prevalence of the avalanche prone locations will increase in the afternoon. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Gliding avalanches can also occur at any time. Areas with glide cracks are to be avoided as far as possible. &lt;br/&gt; As the temperature drops hardly any more moist avalanches are possible.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Over a wide area 10 to 20 cm of snow will fall above approximately 2000 m. In some localities 0 to 5 cm of snow fell yesterday above approximately 2000 m. &lt;br/&gt; Steep sunny slopes: As a consequence of highly fluctuating temperatures a crust formed on the surface during the last few days. &lt;br/&gt; Especially below approximately 2500 m sunny slopes: Relatively hard layers of snow are lying on a moist old snowpack. &lt;br/&gt; In shady places that are protected from the wind: Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. &lt;br/&gt; Especially steep north, northeast and northwest facing slopes: Towards its base, the snowpack consists of faceted crystals. &lt;br/&gt; Snow depths vary greatly above approximately 2200 m, depending on the infuence of the wind. Adjacent to ridgelines and in pass areas and at high altitude a little snow is lying. At low altitude less snow than usual is lying. &lt;br/&gt; In the south-east of the region, watch out for the numerous rocks hidden by the little recent snow.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>As a consequence of the ceasing of precipitation there will be only a very slight increase in the danger of dry avalanches.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
