<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4222RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-02-15T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4222RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-02-15T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-02-16T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1400Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_1400Lo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>&gt;ca. 2400 m oft überdeckt in Kammlagen, Rinnen und Mulden - mit der Seehöhe zunehmend</comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>&lt;2600 m: glide-snow avalanches on steep smooth slopes; increasing wet-snow avalanches due to warmth</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Fresh snowdrifts at high altitudes. Glide-snow/wet-snow avalanches due to warmth.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>For winter sports enthusiasts, predominantly favorable conditions prevail with moderate avalanche danger. In high ridgeline terrain, in gullies and bowls, freshly generated snowdrift accumulations require special attentiveness: they are often blanketed by fresher snowdrifts and are trigger-prone. Danger zones increase with ascending altitude. One winter sports enthusiast can trigger a medium-sized slab avalanche. Apart from the dangers of being buried in snow masses, the risks of being swept along and forced to take a fall also need consideration. Beware cornices on ridges. Glide-snow avalanches are difficult to forecast or estimate. They can trigger in all aspects below 2600 m at any time of day or night and grow to medium size. Caution below glide cracks. Loose-snow slides possible on very steep sunny slopes.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>At high altitudes, older snowdrift accumulations lie mostly atop a stable old snowpack, on steep shady slopes, often atop soft layers. Covered drifts at high altitudes often lie atop a snowpack with weak near-surface layers, are thus prone to triggering. The warm ground and wet snowpack base reinforce gliding snowpack movements. Below 1400 m there is very little snow on the ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>Nocturnal hours: Dry, only partially clear skies. Friday daytime:  Mild, intermittently sunny. Zero-degre level at 3000 m. At 2000 m: +7 degrees. Light-to-moderate W/SW winds.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Slight perturbance on Friday night will bring minor snowfall above 1500-1800 m, accompanied by temporary winds and lower temperatures.The danger of dry-snow avalanches could increase somewhat on Sunday. Danger of glide-snow/wet-snow avalanches not change much with the lower temperatures.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-05-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-05-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-03-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-03-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-08-07"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
