<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4602RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-03-30T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4602RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-03-30T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-03-31T16:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <comment>possible at any time of day or night</comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment>hefty impulse of warmth</comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Storm-strength southerly foehn wind</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Wet-snow problem, esp. in steep sunny terrain, rocky terrain is often the starting zone. Danger zones increase with solar radiation. Larger avalanches are possible in isolated cases, also in low altitude, flat-terrain zones.&#13;
Gliding snow problem in all aspects, esp. on steep grass-covered slopes. Starting zone: glide-cracks and shooting cracks. Avoid zones near them! They are possible at any time of day or night. Larger avalanches are possible in isolated cases, also in low altitude, flat-terrain zones.&#13;
Snowdrift problem: danger zones have decreased, likeliest in extended north-facing terrain near the high peaks of Niedere Tauern and Dachstein.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>High temperatures over the last few days have done harsh work on the snowpack, it has forfeited its firmness. The snow base is wet, the surface generally soft already in early morning. In spite of storm-strength winds, hardly any new snowdrifts have been generated. But gliding snow masses have increased. The slopes are becoming bare of snow.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <wxSynopsisComment>A stormy SW airstream has generated weather conditions in the Eastern Alps since 26 March. On Easter Sunday the stormy southerly foehn wind will persist, hefty gusts will batter the foehn lanes on the northern flank of the Alps, also ridgeline terrain. Intermittently sunny, clouds from the south will lodge against the mountain flanks in Gurktal/Seetal Alps and towards Niedere Tauern. Most sunshine is expected in the western sector of the Northern Alps between Dachstein and Totes Gebirge; least near Turrach, where rain showers can be expected in afternoon. Very warm: zero-degree level at 3000 m.&#13;
On Sunday night a cold front will pass through, promising precipitation and thunderstorms embedded in barrier clouds lodged against the mountain flanks.</wxSynopsisComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger levels are not expected to change significantly. Due to rain penetrating the snowpack and mild temperatures, wet-snow and gliding snow problems remain at the forefront.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-04-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-08-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-09"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-18"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="AT-06-17"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
