<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3895RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-09T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3895RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-09T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-10T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineHi"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineLo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Snowdrifts easily recognizable for experienced individuals - should be avoided</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Above the timberline avalanche danger on the main Allgäu ridge and in the Ammergau, Werdenfels and Berchtesgaden Alps is considerable; below that altitude it is low. Fresh snowdrifts are the main problem. Avalanche prone locations occur esp. in steep ridgeline terrain on S/W/N facing locations and in wind-loaded gullies and bowls. Snowdrift accumulations can be triggered as medium-sized slab avalanches even by minimal additional loading.&#13;
In addition, isolated glide snow avalanches can be expected esp. on very steep slopes with a smooth ground beneath in all aspects - natural triggering is possible. Glide cracks are covered, thus, hard to spot. At higher altitudes these releases can reach medium size.&#13;
On the sunny side spontaneously releasing superficial loose snow avalanches (mostly small) in extremely steep terrain can be expected. </avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>On Tuesday, stormy easterly winds will locally generate snowdrift accumulations that are extremely prone to triggering.The snowdrifts were deposited atop the dry soft snow of the last precipitation period. Shooting cracks indicate that the snowpack structure is prone to triggering. In some places there is a crust at the transitions to the old snowpack surface, underneath which faceted crystals have formed. Elsewhere the old snowpack is thoroughly moist, often wet down to the ground. At lower altitudes, too, where the ground had been totally bare of snow before the recent snowfall, the snowpack is now in many places wet.The consequence are gliding movements of the snowpack over the smooth ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger decreases slowly as result of calm high pressure weather.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-30"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-60"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID3895RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-01-09T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID3895RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-01-09T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-01-10T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineHi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineLo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Caution also urged toward danger of being swept away by small slab avalanches</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Above the timberline avalanche danger in the Allgäu, the Bavarian, and the Chiemgau Pre-Alps is moderate; below that altitude it is low. Fresh snowdrifts are the main problem. Avalanche prone locations occur esp. in steep ridgeline terrain on S/W/N facing locations and in wind-loaded gullies and bowls. In a few places the snowdrifts can be triggered as small slab avalanches even by minimal additional loading. Size and frequency of avalanche prone locations increase with ascending altitude.&#13;
In addition, small glide snow avalanches can release spontaneously and slide over the smooth ground on very steep slopes.&#13;
On the sunny side spontaneously releasing superficial loose snow avalanches (mostly small) in extremely steep terrain can be expected.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>On Tuesday, stormy easterly winds will locally generate small-scale snowdrift accumulations. The snowdrifts were deposited atop the soft snow of the last precipitation period. Shooting cracks indicate that the snowpack structure is prone to triggering. In some places there is a crust at the transitions to the old snowpack surface, underneath which faceted crystals have formed. Elsewhere the old snowpack is thoroughly moist, often wet down to the ground. At lower altitudes, too, where ground had been totally bare of snow before the recent snowfall, the snowpack is now in many places wet. The consequence are gliding movements of the snowpack over the smooth ground.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Avalanche danger decreases slowly as result of calm high pressure weather.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-42"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-43"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-51"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-52"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-41"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
