<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <metaDataProperty>
    <MetaData>
      <dateTimeReport>2025-03-13T10:58:23Z</dateTimeReport>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
    </MetaData>
  </metaDataProperty>
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="8f7933b1-7b8d-4a31-9432-2806507f512d" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-03-13T10:58:23Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-03-12T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-03-13T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-13"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-19"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-08"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Hi"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Lw"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Lw"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-03-13T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-03-14T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Fresh wind slabs represent the main danger.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>As a consequence of new snow and a moderate to strong southeasterly wind, easily released wind slabs formed on Monday. The avalanche prone locations are sometimes covered with new snow and are therefore difficult to recognise. &lt;br/&gt; The fresh snow and the wind slabs can be released easily, even by a single winter sport participant,. This applies especially at transitions from a shallow to a deep snowpack, when entering gullies and bowls for example, as well as on very steep shady slopes. Backcountry touring and other off-piste activities call for meticulous route selection. &lt;br/&gt; Several small and, in isolated cases, medium-sized moist and wet avalanches are possible as the day progresses. This applies in particular on extremely steep slopes below approximately 2600 m, in the event of prolonged bright spells in particular.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>20 to 40 cm of snow, and even more in some localities, fell in the last three days above approximately 2000 m. The wind was moderate to strong in some localities. &lt;br/&gt; The high humditiy gave rise to moistening of the old snowpack in all aspects below approximately 2400 m. &lt;br/&gt; The new snow and wind slabs are lying on a crust on steep sunny slopes. In shady places that are protected from the wind above approximately 2500 m: Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. The new snow and wind slabs are lying on the unfavourable surface of an old snowpack on steep shady slopes above approximately 2400 m. Released avalanches and field observations have confirmed a precarious avalanche situation on very steep shady slopes. &lt;br/&gt; In all aspects less snow than usual is lying. On sunny slopes below approximately 2500 m hardly any snow is lying.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Little snow will fall. The avalanche danger will persist.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="ad6a6050-635c-4405-b037-3eb7cf918d92" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-03-13T10:58:23Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-03-12T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-03-13T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-21"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-22"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-16"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-17"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-14"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-15"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-18"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Hi"/>
              <mainValue>3</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Lw"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_se"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_sw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_s"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Lw"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-03-13T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-03-14T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Wind slabs and wet snow represent the main danger.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>As a consequence of the moderate to strong westerly wind, fresh snow drift accumulations will form. The fresh snow and in particular the wind slabs remain for the foreseeable future prone to triggering in particular on very steep northwest, north and northeast facing slopes. They can be released by a single winter sport participant, in particular at transitions from a shallow to a deep snowpack, when entering gullies and bowls for example. &lt;br/&gt; The avalanche prone locations are sometimes covered with new snow and are therefore difficult to recognise. Backcountry touring and other off-piste activities call for meticulous route selection. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Several small and medium-sized moist and wet avalanches are possible as the day progresses, in the event of prolonged bright spells in particular, caution is to be exercised on extremely steep slopes, as well as in steep rocky terrain. &lt;br/&gt; Gliding avalanches are possible even now. Areas with glide cracks are to be avoided as far as possible.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>15 to 25 cm of snow fell in the last three days above approximately 2000 m. &lt;br/&gt; The high humditiy gave rise to moistening of the old snowpack in all aspects below approximately 2400 m. &lt;br/&gt; The new snow and wind slabs are lying on a crust on steep sunny slopes. In shady places that are protected from the wind above approximately 2500 m: Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. The new snow and wind slabs are lying on the unfavourable surface of an old snowpack on steep shady slopes above approximately 2500 m. Whumpfing sounds and the formation of shooting cracks when stepping on the snowpack and released avalanches have confirmed a sometimes treacherous avalanche situation on very steep shady slopes. &lt;br/&gt; In all aspects less snow than usual is lying. On sunny slopes below approximately 2400 m hardly any snow is lying.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Some snow will fall. The avalanche danger will persist.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="664edf13-8003-4312-8e3b-afa0b125c07a" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-03-13T10:58:23Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-03-12T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-03-13T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-23"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-24"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-25"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-26"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-09"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-07"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Hi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Lw"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2400Hi"/>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>wet snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_ne"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_e"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_nw"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_n"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_w"/>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_2500Lw"/>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-03-13T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-03-14T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>Fresh wind slabs represent the main danger.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>As a consequence of a moderate to strong wind from westerly directions, further wind slabs will form. The avalanche prone locations are sometimes covered with new snow and are therefore difficult to recognise. &lt;br/&gt; The fresh snow and the wind slabs can be released by a single winter sport participant in some cases. This applies especially at transitions from a shallow to a deep snowpack, when entering gullies and bowls for example, as well as on very steep shady slopes. &lt;br/&gt; Several small and, in isolated cases, medium-sized moist and wet avalanches are possible as a consequence of warming during the day and solar radiation, in particular on extremely steep slopes, as well as in steep rocky terrain below approximately 2600 m, in the event of prolonged bright spells in particular.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>15 to 20 cm of snow fell in the last three days above approximately 2000 m. The wind was moderate to strong in some localities. &lt;br/&gt; The high humditiy gave rise to moistening of the old snowpack in all aspects below approximately 2400 m. The new snow and wind slabs are lying on a crust on steep sunny slopes. In shady places that are protected from the wind above approximately 2500 m: &lt;br/&gt; The new snow and wind slabs are lying on the unfavourable surface of an old snowpack on steep shady slopes above approximately 2400 m. Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. &lt;br/&gt; In all aspects less snow than usual is lying. Adjacent to ridgelines and in pass areas and at high altitude a little snow is lying. At low altitude less snow than usual is lying. On sunny slopes below approximately 2600 m hardly any snow is lying.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Little snow will fall. The avalanche danger will persist.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
