<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4146RGR1">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-02-07T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4146RGR1">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-02-07T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-02-08T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>Small amounts of precipitation</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger is low. Glide snow avalanche danger persists which &#13;
can release naturally at any time on individual steep slopes with smooth&#13;
 ground in any aspect. Releases are mostly small. Avoid zones below &#13;
glide cracks.&#13;
In addition, small-scale snowdrift accumulations are generated at &#13;
high altitudes. Avalanche prone locations are found in steep rigdeline &#13;
terrain as well as in  gullies and bowls in N/E/S aspects. Slab &#13;
avalanches can be released by a single skier. Releases are mostly small.&#13;
 Heed danger of being swept along. Danger of taking a fall on hard &#13;
snowpack surface.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Onset of pecipitations on Wednesday night. At high altitudes the snowfall level will rise during the course of the day.  Below the snowfall level ingress of rain makes the snowpack increasingly moist, forfeits its firmness.The snowpack base is wet. Gliding movements over slopes with smooth ground are possible. Above the snowfall level, brisk westerly winds are generating isolated small snowdrift accumulations which are deposited atop a hard (sometimes icy) old snowpack surface and are prone to triggering. A weak layer consisting of faceted crystals formed underneath the melt-freeze crust in shady summit zones due to the nocturnal outgoing longwave radiation in the last few nights. At intermediate altitude the snowpack becomes more and more shallow; below approximately 1300 m there is barely any snow left.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Weather on the weekend will be milder. The snowpack depth will decrease further. Avalanche danger will not change significantly.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-42"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-43"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-51"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-52"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-41"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-60"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-30"/>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="RID4146RGR2">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2024-02-07T17:00:00+00:00</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation gml:id="BID4146RGR2">
              <name>avalanche-warnings.eu</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2024-02-07T17:00:00+00:00</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2024-02-08T17:00:00+00:00</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineHi"/>
              <mainValue>2</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
            <DangerRating>
              <validElevation xlink:href="ElevationRange_ForestlineLo"/>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>gliding snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SW"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_W"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NW"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
            <AvProblem>
              <type>drifting snow</type>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_N"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_NE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_E"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_SE"/>
              <validAspect xlink:href="AspectRange_S"/>
              <comment></comment>
            </AvProblem>
          </avProblems>
          <avActivityHighlights>At high altitude small-scale snowdrifts</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanche danger above the treeline is moderate. The main problem is gliding snow which can trigger at any time on very steep slopes with smooth ground in any aspect and reach medium size. Avoid zones below glide cracks.&#13;
In addition, small-scale snowdrift accumulations are generated at high altitudes. Avalanche prone locations are found in steep rigdeline terrain as well as in  gullies and bowls in N/E/S aspects. Slab avalanches can be released by a single skier. Releases are mostly small. Heed danger of being swept along. Danger of taking a fall on hard snowpack surface.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Precipitations will start on Wednesday night. At high altitudes the snowfall level will rise during the course of the day. Below the snowfall level ingress of rain makes the snowpack increasingly moist, forfeits its firmness.The snowpack base is wet. Gliding movements over slopes with smooth ground are to be expected. Above the snowfall level, brisk westerly winds are locally generating small snowdrift accumulations which are deposited atop a hard (sometimes icy) old snowpack surface and are prone to triggering. A weak layer consisting of faceted crystals formed underneath the melt-freeze crust in shady summit zones due to the nocturnal outgoing longwave radiation in the last few nights. Below 1300 m there is barely any snow left.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>Weather on the weekend will be milder. At higher altitudes the snowdrift accumulations can settle; at lower altitudes the snowpack depths continues to decrease. Avalanche danger will recede somewhat.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="DE-BY-11"/>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
