<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<ObsCollection xmlns="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS http://caaml.org/Schemas/V5.0/Profiles/BulletinEAWS/CAAMLv5_BulletinEAWS.xsd">
  <metaDataProperty>
    <MetaData>
      <dateTimeReport>2025-03-08T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
    </MetaData>
  </metaDataProperty>
  <observations>
    <Bulletin gml:id="b623c89a-46a0-4f9e-bd72-43b0c43c13a5" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-03-08T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-03-08T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-03-09T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-10"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-11"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-05"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-06"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-25"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-26"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-09"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-07"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-08"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems/>
          <tendency>
            <type>increasing</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-03-09T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-03-10T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>The snow sport conditions outside marked and open pistes remain quite favourable. In the evening as a consequence of new snow and strong wind there will be an increase in the avalanche danger.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Very isolated avalanche prone locations are to be found on extremely steep northwest, north and northeast facing slopes in high Alpine regions. Avalanches can be released in the old snowpack by large loads. &lt;br/&gt; There is a danger of falling on the hard snow surface, in particular on very steep sunny slopes. &lt;br/&gt; New snow in the evening. 15 to 30 cm of snow, and up to 40 cm in some localities, will fall until Monday above approximately 1500 m. The maximum amounts of fresh snow will be reached in the areas bordering Piedmont. The wind will be moderate to strong. The prevalence of the avalanche prone locations will increase during the course of the night.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>Sunny slopes: The surface of the snowpack has frozen to form a strong crust and will hardly soften at all. In shady places that are protected from the wind: Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. &lt;br/&gt; In all aspects only a small amount of snow is lying for the time of year. On sunny slopes below approximately 2800 m hardly any snow is lying.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>During the course of the night as a consequence of new snow and strong wind there will be an increase in the avalanche danger.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="a0b287c6-3764-4b80-98c0-198c4ffb4aea" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-03-08T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-03-08T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-03-09T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-20"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-23"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-12"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-01"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-24"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-13"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-02"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-21"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-03"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-04"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-18"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-19"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems/>
          <tendency>
            <type>increasing</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-03-09T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-03-10T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>The snow sport conditions outside marked and open pistes remain quite favourable. In the evening as a consequence of new snow and strong wind there will be only a slight increase in the avalanche danger.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanches can in very isolated cases be released in the old snowpack, especially on very steep shady slopes in little used backcountry terrain. Restraint should be exercised because avalanches can sweep people along and give rise to falls. &lt;br/&gt; New snow in the evening. 15 to 30 cm of snow, and up to 40 cm in some localities, will fall until Monday above approximately 1400 m. The maximum quantities of fresh snow can be reached in the headlands of the Gran Paradiso Valleys. The prevalence of the avalanche prone locations will increase during the course of the night.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The wind was light. &lt;br/&gt; Sunny slopes: The surface of the snowpack has frozen to form a strong crust and will hardly soften at all. In shady places that are protected from the wind: Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. &lt;br/&gt; Snow depths vary greatly above approximately 2200 m, depending on the infuence of the wind. Adjacent to ridgelines and in pass areas and at high altitude a little snow is lying. At low altitude less snow than usual is lying. Below approximately 2200 m no snow is lying on south facing slopes.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>During the course of the night as a consequence of new snow and strong wind there will be an increase in the avalanche danger.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
    <Bulletin gml:id="ae2df06a-78d8-4771-8eac-f7e481e1670f" xml:lang="en">
      <metaDataProperty>
        <MetaData>
          <dateTimeReport>2025-03-08T16:00:00Z</dateTimeReport>
          <srcRef>
            <Operation>
              <name>Avalanche.report</name>
            </Operation>
          </srcRef>
        </MetaData>
      </metaDataProperty>
      <validTime>
        <TimePeriod>
          <beginPosition>2025-03-08T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
          <endPosition>2025-03-09T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
        </TimePeriod>
      </validTime>
      <srcRef>
        <Operation>
          <name>Avalanche.report</name>
        </Operation>
      </srcRef>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-22"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-16"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-17"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-14"/>
      <locRef xlink:href="IT-23-AO-15"/>
      <bulletinResultsOf>
        <BulletinMeasurements>
          <dangerRatings>
            <DangerRating>
              <mainValue>1</mainValue>
            </DangerRating>
          </dangerRatings>
          <avProblems/>
          <tendency>
            <type>steady</type>
            <validTime>
              <TimePeriod>
                <beginPosition>2025-03-09T23:00:00Z</beginPosition>
                <endPosition>2025-03-10T23:00:00Z</endPosition>
              </TimePeriod>
            </validTime>
          </tendency>
          <avActivityHighlights>The snow sport conditions outside marked and open pistes are quite favourable.</avActivityHighlights>
          <avActivityComment>Avalanches can in very isolated cases be released in the old snowpack, especially on very steep shady slopes in little used backcountry terrain. This applies especially above approximately 2700 m along the border with France and along the border between Valais and Italy. &lt;br/&gt; Restraint should be exercised because avalanches can sweep people along and give rise to falls.</avActivityComment>
          <snowpackStructureComment>The wind was light. &lt;br/&gt; Sunny slopes: The surface of the snowpack has frozen to form a strong crust and will soften during the day. In shady places that are protected from the wind: Towards its surface, the snowpack is dry and has a loosely bonded surface. &lt;br/&gt; Snow depths vary greatly above approximately 2200 m, depending on the infuence of the wind. Adjacent to ridgelines and in pass areas and at high altitude a little snow is lying. At low altitude less snow than usual is lying.</snowpackStructureComment>
          <tendencyComment>A little new snow above approximately 1300 m: During the night as a consequence of new snow and strong wind there will be only a slight increase in the avalanche danger.</tendencyComment>
        </BulletinMeasurements>
      </bulletinResultsOf>
    </Bulletin>
  </observations>
</ObsCollection>
